Mss.497.3.R114
American Philosophical Society
Paul Radin papers, [ca. 1912-1959]
Circa 1912-1959
Mss.497.3.R114
American Philosophical Society
12.5 Linear feet
12.5 linear feet.
There are notes, transcriptions, essays, etc., on the language and customs of several Indian tribes. There are numerous vocabularies, dictionaries, and grammatical notes on the Winnebago, Patwin, and Huave tribes, and some items on the Fox, Tukudh, Pomo, Wappo, and Wintu; 79 notebooks, in English and Winnebago, on myths, legends, stories, customs, dances, religious observances, costume, etc., of the Winnebago, with some on the Ottawa and Ojibwa; notes on Winnebago history; 2 boxes of Winnebago phonetic texts; and significant material on Mexican Indians (Zapotec). Some of the items are typed copies of Radin's published studies.
Miskwanda
Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
Box 1-24
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift from Doris Radin and accessioned, 07/--/1960 (1268ms) and 1972. Bibliographic card file: gift from Dell H. Hymes and accessioned, 05/01/1984 (504ms). See in-house shelf list for additional dates and accession numbers.
Scope and Contents note
Native American Images note: Nearly 400 black and white silver gelatin photographs; watercolor, pencil and ink sketches; postcards; and photomechanical prints of Ojibwa ethnology of L’Arbre Croche (Crooked Tree), Cross Village and Middle Village, Michigan, 1917-1926. Collected while Radin worked for the Geological Survey of Canada, the bulk of the drawings are by Native American consultant Miskwanda. The images include face painting, hunting and fishing equipment, diagrams of dances and games, musical instruments, dwellings and clothes. Of note, original pencil sketch maps of a battle between the Ottawa and Mackado tribes and ink sketches of feather head-dress arrangements in war and in peace. Microfilm negatives are available, Film numbers 372.8 and 1396. Referenced in Freeman’s Guide to manuscripts relating to the American Indian.
Biographical/Historical note
Anthropologist Paul Radin researched the language and folklore of North American and Mexican Indians, the Winnebago, Ojibwa, and Zapotec in particular.
Anthropological linguistics; Anthropology; Dictionaries.; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Face painting; Folklore; Fox language; Gelatin silver prints; Huave language; Indians of Mexico--Languages; Indians of North America--Folklore; Indians of North America--Languages; Indians of North America--Michigan; Notebooks.; Notes.; Ojibwa Indians; Ojibwa Indians--Michigan--Folklore; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ottawa Indians--Social life and customs; Photomechanical prints; Pomo language; Postcards; Sketches.; Tukuarika Indians; Vocabularies.; Wappo dialect; Watercolor drawings; Winnebago Indians; Winnebago language; Wintun languages; Zapotec language
- Native American linguistics collection, n.d.; 497.3 R114.1; 5.0 Volume(s); Includes Ojibwa miscellany; Huave word list; Winnebago word list; Wintun-English dictionary; remarks on Utoaztecan and Macro-Penutian.; 5 volumes. (Volume 5)
- Crooked Tree, Michigan, 1926
- Mxkadege kopmagon, 1926
- Ojibwa child, 1926
- Ojibwa man-Pine clan, 1926
- Ojibwa war customs, 1917-1926
- Ojibwa war dance, 1926
- Ottawa peace horn flute, 1926
- Standing Rock, Michigan, 1926
- Chinantec Dictionary